<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Learning With Omar</title>
    <link>https://omar2cloud.github.io/rasp/pi/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Learning With Omar</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://omar2cloud.github.io/rasp/pi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://omar2cloud.github.io/rasp/pi/_grafana/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://omar2cloud.github.io/rasp/pi/_grafana/</guid>
      <description>What is Grafana? Grafana is an open source visualization, analytics and alerting platform. It turns time series database data into well designed graphs for visualizations on dashboards.
To learn more about Grafana.
Part 3: Install Grafana: 1- Installing Grafana from the APT repository allows it to automatically get updated when apt-get update is ran. Let&amp;rsquo;s install the latest OSS release:
sudo apt-get install -y apt-transport-httpssudo apt-get install -y software-properties-common wgetwget -q -O - https://packages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://omar2cloud.github.io/rasp/pi/_influxdb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://omar2cloud.github.io/rasp/pi/_influxdb/</guid>
      <description>What is InfluxDB? InfluxDB is a time series database. It&amp;rsquo;s engineered to build IoT, analytics and monitoring. It is built to ingest millions of data points per second produced by sensors, systems, applications and infrastructure. By the end of this tutorial, we would have installed InfluxDB to monitor our Raspberry Pi 4 system&amp;rsquo;s metrics such as CPU, Disk space and memory.
To learn more about InfluxDB.
Part 1: Install InfluxDB 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://omar2cloud.github.io/rasp/pi/_telegraf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://omar2cloud.github.io/rasp/pi/_telegraf/</guid>
      <description>What is Telegraf? Telegraf is an open source server agent written in Go. It is built to collect metrics from a wide array of inputs and write them into a wide array of outputs.
To learn more about Telegraf.
Part 2: Install Telegraf: 1- We will install the latest version of Telegraf using the ap-get package manager. Firstly, let&amp;rsquo;s add the InfluxData repository by running the following commands (you could copy and paste all commands at once on the terminal, or one line at a time):</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
